제작 - 네이트 드라마 24 자막팀
http://club.nate.com/24
위스콘신주 포인트 플레이스
Point Place, Wisconsin
1976년 10월 23일
October 23, 1976
저녁 9시 37분
9:37 p.m.
에릭네 차고 앞
Eric Forman's Driveway
젠장!
Damn!
켈소 선수 또 실패했군요
Kelso misses another one.
너 세번 놓쳤으니까 호어(H-O-R) 맞지?
슛을 실패하면 HORSE 한글자씩 늘어남
I believe that's H-O-R.
아, 너 남창이구나(whore)
You are a whore.
아냐! 이건 HORSE 게임이야
No, the game is Horse.
있지, 마이클?
난 집에 갈꺼야
Okay. You know what, Michael?
I'm gonna go home.
가서 숙제나 할래
I'm gonna do my homework.
토요일 밤에 숙제를 한다고?
You do your homework
on a Saturday night?
그래
Yeah.
봐, 난 말야
Look, I mean, look at me.
월요일까지 1000단어
작문숙제 해가야 되는데
I've got a 1,000-word
term paper due Monday...
별로 신경 안쓰고 있는 거 보이지?
일요일 날 하루종일 하면 되니까
but you don't see me sweating. I've
got a whole crappy Sunday to do it.
재키, 가지마
Jackie, don't go home.
스티브 마틴이 "새러데이 나잇
라이브" 사회를 볼 거란 말야
I mean, Steve Martin's hosting
Saturday Night,
난 그 쇼 싫어
I hate that show, okay?
거기 나오는 광고가 넌 진짜라고
생각하나 본데 진짜가 아니란 말야
They have commercials that you
think are real but they're not real.
게다가 넌 그것들을
사고 싶어 하잖아
And then you wanna buy the stuff.
나중에 보자, 마이클
Okay. See you, Michael.
- 잘가, 잘가라!
- 시끄러!
- Bye! Bye-bye!
- Shut up.
켈소, 재키가 토요일 밤에
숙제를 한다잖아
Kelso, Jackie does her homework
on Saturday night.
너무 우울하겠다
That's so hip.
니들 더이상 재키 걱정은 안해도
될 꺼야, 난 걔랑 끝낼 거니까
You guys don't have to worry
about Jackie anymore...
'cause I'm breaking up with her.
그 얘기 정말 지겹다
We are so tired of
hearing you say that.
아냐, 정말 끝낼 거란 말야
No. I am. I'm breaking up with her.
그래? 언제?
Yeah, when?
기회를 보고 있는 거야
I'm picking my moment.
페즈는 어디 갔냐?
Where's Fez?
여기서 던져봐, 남창아!
HORSE 게임은 앞사람이
성공한 곳에서 던져야 한다
Make that shot, whore.
토퍼 그레이스 (에릭 포먼)
밀라 커니스 (재키 벅하트)
애쉬튼 커쳐 (마이클 켈소)
대니 메스털슨 (스티븐 하이드)
로라 프레폰 (도나 핀씨오티)
윌머 발더라마 (페즈)
데브라 조 러프 (키티 포먼)
커트우드 스미스 (레드 포먼)
타냐 로버츠 (미지 핀씨오티)
돈 스탁 (밥 핀씨오티)
That '70s Show 자막팀
영문자막 : 김민경(paramount@nate)
싱크수정, 번역 : 김현정(fuchs@nate)
That '70s Show 자막팀
영문자막 : 김민경(paramount@nate)
싱크수정 : 김현정(fuchs@nate)
1x10 Sunday, Bloody Sunday
Nov 29, 1998 on FOX
오늘 아침엔 와플이 특별히
더 맛있는 것 같지 않니?
Now, aren't the waffles extra
delicious this wonderful morning?
또 금연하시는 거예요?
Did you quit smoking again?
그런 건 왜 묻니?
And why do you ask, little one?
엄마가 백설공주처럼 말하시는거
보니까, 제 생각엔 딱...
You're talking like Snow White,
so I figured...
에릭!
Eric!
잘 생각하셨어요
꼭 성공하시길 바래요
Which is great,
I really want you to quit.
옛날에 끊었어야 했어
I should've quit a long time ago.
난 간호사잖니. 남들보다 더 잘 알아
소세지 더 먹을래?
I'm a nurse. I know better.
More sausage?
내가 받을게
I'll get it.
여보세요?
Hello?
오, 그거 너무 안됐네요
That's too bad.
그럼요, 저희야 좋죠
Sure. Be glad to.
네, 곧 뵙죠. 들어가세요
Yeah. See you soon. Goodbye.
- 누구예요?
- 어머니
- Who was that, dear?
- My mother.
그게 말이지..
Seems like...
폴 삼촌이 발목이 부러지셨나봐
Uncle Paul broke his ankle...
그래서 오늘은 우리와
교회에 가시겠대
and she's going to
church with us today.
아뇨, 안 돼요
No, she's not.
- 이번엔 폴 삼촌 차례잖아요
- 발목이 부러졌다잖아
- It's Paul's turn to take her.
- Like I said, he broke his ankle.
발목이 부러졌든 어쨌든
그 분 차례예요
Broken ankle, whatever.
It's his turn.
- 여보, 그 양반 다치셨다고
- 알아요, 얼마나 좋으실까요
- Kitty, the man is injured.
- Okay. That is just great.
냉동실에서 닭을 꺼내놔야겠어요
I will just take a chicken
out of the freezer...
우리 버니스 여왕님께서는
because queen Bernice...
햄을 싫어하시니까요
doesn't like ham.
알았어, 어머님께 전화해서
안되겠다고 말씀드릴게
Okay, look, I'll just call her
and tell her we can't make it.
여보, 여보, 여보
그러면 누가 욕 먹을지 알잖아요
Red. You know who'll
get blamed for that.
왜 당신한테 욕을 하시겠어?
내 어머니신데
Why should she blame you?
She's my mother.
그 양반 저한테
그냥 넘어가는 법이 없단 말예요
Something she never
lets me forget.
저기요, 제가 아프다고
말씀드려 보세요
Look, you could tell her
I'm sick or something.
에릭, 위에 올라가서
할머니가 사준 셔츠 입거라
Eric, go upstairs...
and put on that shirt
your grandmother gave you.
에릭, 그냥 있어라. 네 엄마가
우스운 짓을 하고 있구나
Eric, just stay there.
Your mother is just being ridiculous.
진짜 웃기는 짓은 당신 어머니한테
우리집 전화번호 알려준 거예요
You know what's ridiculous, is
giving your mother our phone number.
- 당신이야말로 정말...
- 그만요
- What's being ridiculous is...
- Hold it.
그만들하고 들어 보세요..
Hold it. Now, look...
진정들 하시구요
let's just stay calm.
엄마, 원하시면
제가 할머니랑 놀아드릴게요
Mom, if it'll help you out,
I'll hang out with Grandma...
그러면 엄마를
가만 나두실 거예요
so she'll leave you alone.
어떠세요?
What do you say?
무엇보다도 에릭
나만 "그만"이라는 소리를 할 수 있다
First of all, Eric,
I'm the one who says "hold it."
"그만" 소리는 네가 청구서 요금을
내게 되거든 그때 가서나 해
When you pay the bills,
you get to say "hold it."
그리고 차에 타라, 교회도 가고
빌어먹을 멋진 일요일을 보낼 거니까
Now get in the car,
'cause we're going to church...
and we're gonna have
a damn nice Sunday.
빌어먹을 잘 나셨수
어디 한번 날 말려 보구랴
You're damn right.
Just try and stop me.
빌어먹을
Damn.
저기 오시네요
Here she comes.
여보, 나 도저히 못할 거 같아요
God, Red, I don't think
I can do this.
- 여보, 우릴 위해서라도 웃어
- 알았어요
- Kitty, do us all a favor and light up.
- I'm fine.
조심하세요,할머니
Careful, Grandma.
옷이었구나
It's just my dress.
안녕하셨어요, 어머니
It's nice to see you, Bernice.
난 이 차가 싫다
알았니? 이 차가 그냥 싫어
I hate this car.
You know, I just hate this car.
네 형 제리 차는 멋지단다
'링컨' 말이야
Your brother Jerry has
a beautiful car. A Lincoln.
하긴 걔가 너보다 돈을
많이, 훨씬 많이 벌긴 하지
But then, he makes more money,
a lot more money than you do.
좋아요, 그럼 가죠
All righty, then.
애야, 에릭이 그러는데
네가 담배 끊었다며?
So, Kitty, Eric tells me
that you quit smoking.
네 끊었어요, 그래서..
기분이 아주 좋아요
Yes, I did quit. And I just...
I feel great.
잘했구나, 아가
Good for you, dear.
성부와 성자와
성령님의 이름으로, 아멘
In the name of the Father,
the Son and the Holy Ghost. Amen.
이제 일어나서 묵상하시겠습니다
Please stand for a moment
of silent meditation.
하나님, 담배를 끊도록
도와주셔서 감사합니다
Dear God, Thank you so much
for helping me quit,,,
그렇게 추악하고 역거운....
such a filthy, disgusting,,,
시름을 달래주는 달콤한 습관을요
soothing, delicious habit,
하나님, 전 안되겠어요
아니에요, 전 괜찮아요, 아멘
God, I can't do this,
No, I'm fine, Amen,
하나님...
Dear God,,,
미련한 폴란드 것들은
어찌해야 합니까?
what's with all the Polacks?
하나님
Dear God,
당신도 쉬시는 날에
귀찮게 하고 싶진 않지만
I don't mean to bother you
on your day off,,,
전 할머니를 책임지기로 약속했고
내일까지 낼 기말리포트도 있습니다
but I promised to help out with Grandma
and I have a term paper due tomorrow,
그러니까 할머니가
오늘 일찍 가게 해주시거나
If you could either
get her to leave early today,,,
아니면 내일 학교에
불이 나게 해주시면
or burn down the school tomorrow,
둘 중 하나라도요
당신께서 결정하세요
I mean, either or, God's choice,
정말 절 구원하시는 거예요
하나님, 주님, 아멘
It'd really help me out, man,
God, Lord, Amen,
거룩하신 주님
Dear Lord,
패커스가 우승하게 해주시면
어디 덧 납니까? 아멘
Would it kill you to give the Packers
a winning season? Amen,
그리고 제 사랑스런 가족을 지켜주십쇼
어쩌고 저쩌고
And watch over my loving family
blah, blah, blah,
"고통받는 자들의 예배" 시간입니다
교회에 못가는 환자 등을 위한 TV 예배
Welcome to
Worship for Shutins.
돌려
Change it.
됐어, 돌려
All right, change that.
페즈가 오기 전엔
어떻게 채널을 돌렸었더라?
How did we change channels
before Fez? / I don't think we did.
안 돌렸을껄
얘들아! 나 기말리포트 써야 돼
You guys, I gotta work on my
term paper. / Where's Grandma?
할머니는 어디 계셔?
욕실에 계셔, 그러니까 한 20분에서
30분 정도 시간이 있어
She's in the bathroom, so I've got,
like, 20 minutes, half hour tops.
과제물이 뭔데?
- What's the assignment?
- All right.
"미국 정부 3대 기관과 각각의 기능에
대해 1000 단어로 쓰시오"
"In 1,000 words describe
the three branches...
"of the United States government
and their functions."
도저히 못하겠다
I'll never make it.
올라가서 숙제해야 한다고 말씀드려
Go up and tell them
you have homework to do.
안돼, 난 가정의 평화를 지키고 싶어
No, I wanna keep
peace in the family.
그래, 도나, 포먼은 홀마크 카드에
나오는 가족을 원하는 거야
세계 최대 엽서 및 카드 회사
Yeah, Donna, Forman wants
the Hallmark card family.
- 뭐?
- 그 왜, 할머니가 오시고
- The what?
- You know, Grandma comes over.
-이렇게 아름다운 일요일에
시어머님께-
To my mother-in-law
on this beautiful Sunday,
어머님의 웃는 얼굴과
Your smiling face,,,
어머님의 다정한 포옹 덕에
우린 집은 행복한 곳이 됐답니다
your kind embrace
has made my home a happy place,
나도 내 사랑하는 아들이
너와 맺어져서 너무 행복하단다
And I'm so happy you're the one,,,
to whom I gave my loving son,
두분이 행복하다니
나도 너무 행복해요
And I'm so happy
you're both happy,,,
그렇지 않았으면
너무 짜증났을 테니까요
'cause otherwise life
would be crappy,
그런게 아냐
I don't want that.
아니긴, 그 크고 희망에 찬 눈을
보면 다 알아
Yeah, you do. I can see it
in those wide, hopeful eyes.
그렇지만 현실은 이렇지
But the reality is this:
며느리에게
넌 내 아들을 뺏어갔어
To my daughter-in-law,
you took my son,
어머님은 제 삶을 망쳐 놓으셨어요
You wrecked my life,
넌 내 젊음을 날려버렸어
You stole my youth,
어머닌 제 아내를 미워하세요
You hate my wife,
전 최선을 다 했어요
I do my best,
농담이겠지
Now, that's a joke,
전 나갈 거예요
I'm going out,
난 담배가 필요해
I need a smoke,
젠장, 에릭!
Damn it, Eric!
네 할머니 피해다니지 마라
그 양반은 늙고..
Quit hiding from your
grandmother. She's old,
돌아가실 수도 있어
얼른 가봐!
she could die. Now, move it!
- 욕실에 계신 줄 알았는데요
- 아니야
- I thought she was in the bathroom.
- False alarm.
가서 할머니를 돌봐 드려
이건 우리가 해 줄게
Look, go take care of your
grandmother. We can do this.
고마워
Thanks.
- 그래서 몇자나 적어놨는데?
- 이름, 날짜, 반
All right, how many words does he
have? / His name, the date, the class.
일곱 단어
Seven.
쟨 망했다
- He's screwed.
- Use his middle name.
걔 중간 이름을 써
봤지? 나한테는 이런 일이 절대 없어
See? Now, this would
never happen to me.
난 토요일에 숙제를 다 하니까
That is why I do my homework
on Saturday.
지금이 기회야, 켈소
잡아
This is a moment, Kelso. Pick it.
너희들은 다
날 본받아야 될 거 같다
I think you all could learn
something from me right now.
두번째 기회?!
Moment number two.
좋아, 재키
우리 얘기 좀 하자
All right. Jackie, we need to talk.
있잖아?
You know what?
나 작년 역사 수업때 이 리포트 썼었어
그때 "A" 받았던 것 같아
I did the same paper last year
in history. I think I got an "A"
집에 가서 가져올까?
You want me to go home and get it?
생각 좀 해보고
- Let me think. Yeah!
- Hold on, Donna.
그래!
잠깐만, 도나
재키, 우리 얘기 좀 하자
이 모든...
Jackie, we need to talk
about this whole...
재키, 얼른 갔다 와
Jackie, why don't you go ahead?
알았어
Okay.
아직 끝내지 마
알았어?
Do not break up with her yet,
you understand me?
알았다고 말해
Say you understand me.
난 항상 니가 재키를
싫어하는 줄 알았는데
All this time I thought
you didn't like Jackie.
그냥 아직 끝내지 말란 말야
Just don't break up with her yet.
알았어, 알았다고
Okay.
야, 재키한테 뭘 바라는데?
이런 건 걔보다 내가 더 잘 알아
What do I need Jackie for, man?
I know more about this stuff than she does.
정부의 진짜 3대 기관은
군대, 기업, 헐리우드야
The three true branches of the government
are military, corporate, and Hollywood.
연필 줘봐, 내가 해줄게
I need a pencil. I got it.
재키, 빨리 가!
Jackie, run!
Love!
닭요리가 곧 다 될텐데
시장하셨으면 좋겠네요
I hope you're hungry.
Yup, the chicken will be done soon.
난 닭고기 못 먹는다
내가 과민성 장 증후군인거 알잖니
I can't eat chicken.
You know I have an irritable bowel.
햄요리를 했어야지
You should have made a ham.
맞다, 할머니...
Boy, Grandma...
오늘 아침 설교
정말 훌륭하지 않았어요?
that was a great service this morning.
Don't you think?
내 생각에 목사님이 관용에 대해서
너무 많이 언급하는 것 같더구나
I think the pastor talked too much
about forgiveness.
어떤 인간들은 용서해서는
안 되는데 말야
Some people shouldn't be forgiven.
그건 신학이 부자들을..
This is why theology is such a rich...
있죠, 어머님. 어떤 사람들은
용서를 필요로 하는 게 아니라
You know, Bernice,
some people don't need forgiveness...
약간의 이해를 필요로 한답니다
they just need a little understanding.
맞아요, 뮤지컬 "가스펠"
보신 적 있으세요?
Too true. Have you seen Godspell?
내가 이해를 못하겠는 건 말이다
You know, what I don't understand...
우리 레드처럼 훌륭한 젊은이가 어떻게
모든걸 내던질 수 있었나 하는 거란다
is how in hell a brilliant young man,
like my Red...
could have thrown away everything.
할머니! 우리 거실로 가요
제가 발마사지 해드릴게요
Grandma! Why don't we go into
the living room and I'll rub your feet.
정말 착하구나
What a wonderful boy.
Look at how thin you are.
너 너무 말랐구나
네 엄마가 밥은 해주고 있는 거냐?
Is your mother
feeding you enough?
우리집에 와서 나랑 살자꾸나
You should come
and live with me.
아니에요
No.
차고에 가려던 참이었어요
I was just on my way to the garage.
이거 좀 고치려고요
To fix this.
아빠, 그냥 축구보셔도 돼요
Dad, just watch your game.
아니다, 그냥 패커스 경긴데 뭐
No, it's just the Packers.
- 에릭, 어디 숨어있었니?
- 숙제하고 있었어요
- Eric, where've you been hiding?
- I've been doing some homework.
그거 아주 중요하지
That's important.
네, 사실 아주 흥미로운 게...
Yeah. You know, actually,
it's a really interesting...
에릭, 잔소리 그만 하고
맛사지나 하렴
Eric, a little less talk
and a little more rubbing.
넌 남들처럼 내 건막류가
무섭지 않은가 보구나
엄지발가락 안쪽에 생기는 혹
You're the only one who's
not afraid of my bunion.
어머나
Oh, dear.
잘있어, 에릭. 나 간다
Good-bye, Eric,
I am going home now.
페즈, 잠깐만
너 우리 할머니 뵌 적 없지?
No, wait, Fez, you haven't
met Grandma.
안녕하세요, 할머니
Hello, Grandma.
나 살던 마을에선 발을 숭배해요
In my village, we worship feet.
근데 이 강아지들 정말
성스러운 보물이네요
And these dogs are a holy treasure.
마사지해보고 싶니?
- You wanna rub them?
- May I?
그래도 돼?
얼마든지
Knock yourself out.
저기, 아빠
Hey, Dad.
젠장, 에릭!
Damn it, Eric!
그렇게 살금살금 다가오지 마라
특히 이런거 할때는
Don't sneak up on a person
like that when they're doing this.
그 안은 좀 어떠냐?
How's it going in there?
제가 발 마사지 해드렸어요
- I rubbed her feet.
- Now, you're a brave one.
너 아주 용감하구나
다시 들어가 보거라
Better get back in there.
아빠, 다시 안 들어오실 거예요?
Dad, you coming back inside?
에릭
Eric...
난 네 할머니를 정말 사랑한단다
I love your grandmother
very, very much.
그냥 그 양반한테 말을 걸거나
같이 시간 보내는 걸 못할 뿐이야
I just can't talk to her
or spend any time with her.
제가 안에서 할머니
발 마사지한 얘기해드렸나요?
Did I mention that I'm in there
rubbing her feet?
아들아...
You know, son...
가끔 넌 고통을 무릅쓰고도
할 일을 다 하더구나
sometimes you've just gotta
play through the pain.
네?
What?
- 아니다, 그냥 들어가
- 네, 알았어요
- I don't know. Just get back in there.
- Yeah, right.
"그들의 사탕발림식 정책목표들은
"With their sugar-coated ideals...
무지한 대중을 무감각하게
만들기 위해 입안된 거야"
"designed to anesthetize
the ignorant masses.
"왜냐고? 그래야 군대가 기업을
주물러서 세계를 지배할 수 있으니까"
"Why? So that the military
slash corporate branches...
"can carry out world domination."
좋아, 불러준 거 다시 읽어봐
All right, read that back to me.
알았어
Okay.
안 받아 적었냐?
You didn't get that?
그냥 백과사전 보고 하자
All right, let's just use
the encyclopedia.
백과사전에 있는 걸
그냥 베끼자는 거야?
You just want to vomit up facts
from an encyclopedia?
- 그래
- 좋아, 니 맘대로 해
Yes. / Okay, fine. You know what?
Vomit away.
난 그런 짓은 못해
I will not be a part of this, then.
에릭, 너 이 밑에 있니?
Eric, are you down here?
여기 없어요, 아줌마
He's not down here, Mrs. Forman.
도나, 잘 됐다
올라와서 우리랑 식사하자
Donna, good, why don't you
come up and eat with us?
도움이 필요하구나. 넌 말고, 스티븐
할머니가 넌 싫어하시잖니
I need all the help I can get. Not you,
Steven. Grandma doesn't like you.
재수는 좋아가지고
Lucky bastard.
그럼 전 뭐 먹어요?
What am I supposed to eat?
냉동고에서 꺼내 먹으렴
You know, help yourself
to the deep freeze.
그치만 다 얼었잖아요
But everything's frozen.
맞다, 건조기가 있지
And I have a dryer.
여보, 이 치즈 포테이토
정말 맛있어
Honey, these cheesy potatoes
are delicious.
고마워요, 여보
Thank you, honey.
이거 정말 맛있어요, 아줌마
They really are great, Mrs. Forman.
할머니 오시면
항상 이 요리를 먹어
We have them whenever
Grandma comes over...
할머니가 이걸 좋아하시는 걸
엄마가 아시거든. 그렇죠, 할머니?
'cause mom knows how much
she loves them. Right, Grandma?
난 그거 먹으면 아프단다
They make me sick.
유제품에 알러지가 있거든
I'm allergic to dairy.
저런
How sad.
엄마, 위스콘신주에 사시면서
무슨 유제품 알러지예요
위스콘신은 미국 최대의 낙농지역
Ma, this is Wisconsin.
You're not allergic to dairy.
아마 제가 만든 유제품에만
알러지가 생기시겠죠
Maybe she's just allergic
to my dairy.
유제품 알러지가 있으시면
커피에 크림도 넣어서 드시면 안돼요
If you're allergic to dairy you
shouldn't put cream in your coffee.
- 그게, 크림도 유제품이거든요
- 도나, 아냐, 그만해, 알았지?
- I mean, cream is dairy.
- Donna, just, no, okay?
가만 있어봐라, 에릭!
그런데 대체 넌 누구냐?
You shut up, Eric!
Who the hell are you?
할머니, 도나잖아요
16년이나 보셔놓고 그러세요
Grandma, that's Donna,
you've known her for 16 years.
그런적 없다. 어쨌든 난 네 새 친구가
더 맘에 드는구나
I have not. Anyway, I like
your new friend better.
감정도 오고 가는게 있어야죠
The feeling is mutual.
다 먹었어
Done.
차고에서 무슨 소리가 나는군
I heard a noise in the garage.
너구리들이야
Raccoons.
나 갈게
Bye.
한 입도 더 못 먹겠어요
I couldn't eat another bite.
많이 먹었나 봐요
I've had enough.
전 다시 내려갈게요
실례하겠습니다
I'm going back downstairs.
Excuse me.
우리 로렌스 윌크 쇼 볼까요, 할머니?
So, what say we watch
Lawrence Welk, Grandma?
아니, 난 새 친구랑 같이 볼거야
No, I'm going to watch
Lawrence Welk with my new friend.
다시 발 마사지해야지
지명타자 양반?
You up for another foot rub, Desi?
다 됐다
Fry time.
- 앗 뜨거! 뜨거!
- 뭐 하냐?
- Hot! Hot!
- What are you doing?
튀김 먹으면서
네 리포트 쓰고 있어
Just working on your report here,
and having some fries.
잠깐만, 너 엄마 건조기에다
감자튀김 돌린거야?
Wait, you put French fries
in my mom's dryer?
그래, 생선 튀김은 너무
바스러 지더라고, 그래서..
Yeah, the fish sticks
are too flaky, so I just...
말은 해서 뭐해..
I don't even need to...
어디 갔다가 인제 와?
Finally.
Where have you guys been?
리포트를 바로 못 찾았어
We had to look for
the paper, and eat...
그러다 뭐도 좀 먹고
거기다 무슨 일도 좀 있었어
and then some stuff happened, you know.
- 너 셔츠 뒤집어 입었어
- 그래, 이게 그 무슨 일이야
- Your shirt's on inside out.
- Yeah, that's the stuff.
- 리포트 어딨어?
- 맞다, 있잖아?
- Where's the paper?
- Right. Okay, see?
정부 3대 기관에 대한 게 아니라
It wasn't on the three branches
of the government...
4대 음식물에 대한 거였어
it was on the four food groups.
됐어, 우리집에 세계대백과가 있으니까
내가 가서 "G(Government)"편을 가져올께
Okay, look, my dad's got the World Books.
I'll just run next door and get "G."
내가 같이 가줄게
I'll go with you.
너 인제 쟤랑 끝내도 돼
You can break up with her now.
있잖아, 다들 나랑 재키를
찢어 놓으려고 하는데 아주 질렸어
You know, I'm tired of everybody
trying to tear me and Jackie apart.
멍청아, 맨날 쟤랑 끝낼 거라고
노래부른 건 바로 너야
Moron, every day you say
you're breaking up with her.
너네들이 재키를 몰라서 그러는 거야
You guys don't know her like I do.
우린 만나서 장난이나
하는 게 아니란 말야
I mean, it's not just
about fooling around.
걘 나한테 뭘 사준다고
She buys me stuff.
진공청소기로 니 가슴을
빨아줬나 보구나
She hoovered your chest, man.
있잖아?
You know what?
다 필요없어
I don't care anymore.
내 숙제 좀 도와달라고 했더니
아무것도 해준 게 없잖아!
All I wanted was a little help with my
paper and you've done nothing!
니 중간 이름 집어 넣었어
We put your middle name in.
쟝-끌로드?
Jean-Claude?
그래, 두 단어야
That's two words.
너네 정말 치사하다
You guys suck.
정말 도나 밖에 없어
Just thank God for Donna.
나쁜 소식이야, 우리 엄마가 몇권을
벼룩시장에서 팔아 버렸대
Okay, bad news, my mom sold
some out at the garage sale.
그래도, "B", "X", "R" 편은 있어
But we have "B," "X," and "R."
All right.
얘들아, 내가 오늘 정말 심하게
스트레스를 받는구나
Now, you listen up.
I have had an extremely stressful day.
뭐 별로 자랑스러운 얘기는 아니다만
And I am not proud
of what I'm about to say...
누구 담배 좀 줄래?
but someone give me a cigarette!
당장!
Now!
엄마, 우리 담배 안 피워요
But, Mom, we don't smoke.
헛소리 그만 해라, 에릭
난 간호사야
Cut the crap, Eric.
I am a nurse.
십대 다섯명 중에 한명은 담배 피우는
거 알아. 한명, 두명, 세명, 네명, 다섯명
I know that one in five teenagers smoke.
One, two, three, four, five.
이제, 내가 눈을 감았다가 뜨면
Now, I'm going to close my eyes,
and when I open them...
이 두 손가락 사이에 담배가 들어와
있는게 좋을 줄 알아라
there had better be
a cigarette between these two fingers.
자, 얘들아, 서둘러!
Come on, people. Hop to!
고맙다
Thank you.
불은?
Light?
키티
Kitty.
어쩐 일이에요, 여보?
There you are, Red.
어머니가 고양이한테 물리셨다길래
그 놈을 찾으러 내려왔어
Ma says the cat bit her,
so I'm down here looking for it.
아빠, 우리 고양이 안 키우잖아요
Dad, we don't have a cat.
나도 안다
That's what I thought.
있잖니, 우리...
You know, we really...
그 가엾은 외국 아이를 할머니랑
둘이만 남겨 둬야 될 거 같구나
We shouldn't leave
your poor little foreign friend...
up there alone with Grandma.
이 밑은 너무 좋구나
It's really kind of nice down here.
멋진 저녁식사 고마웠다
Thank you for a wonderful dinner.
- 천만에요
- 나 때문에 괜히 귀찮지나 않았는지
- You are so very welcome.
- I hope I wasn't any bother.
엄마, 귀찮긴요
언제 오시든 환영이에요
Ma, you're no bother.
You're as welcome as...
5월의 꽃처럼요
flowers in May.
어머님, 여기요, 가져가시라고
닭고기를 좀 쌌어요
Bernice, here, I wrapped up some
chicken for you to take home.
고맙구나, 얘야
Thank you, dear.
이 안에 치즈 포테이토도
좀 들어있으면 더 좋겠구나
And I hope you put some of those
cheesy potatoes in there.
내가 그걸 얼마나 좋아하는지
너도 알지?
You know how much I love them.
네?
What?
알러지 있다고
난리치실 때는 언제고...
I thought you made such a big deal
about how you were allergic to...
에릭!
Eric!
너무나 멋진 일요일이구나
망치지 마라
This has been a perfectly nice Sunday.
Let's not spoil it.
얘야
Sweetheart...
내가 알러지 문제로
그렇게 심하게 굴진 않았지?
I hope I didn't make too big a deal
about my allergy.
아뇨, 엄마
아직 애잖아요
No, Ma, he's a kid.
저 녀석이 오바한 거예요
He overreacts.
있잖니, 이 쬐그만 차
정말 귀엽구나
You know, this is the cutest little car.
난 이 차가 맘에 든다
I just love it.
825, 826...
Eight hundred and twenty-five,
eight hundred and twenty-six...
에릭, 뭐 하니? 새벽 한시야
Eric, what are you doing?
It's 1:00 in the morning.
지금 막 숙제를 다 했어요
I'm just finishing up some homework.
여긴 왜 내려오셨어요?
What are you doing down here?
백설공주가 구름과자 먹으러 왔단다
Snow White came down
to gun a stick.
엄마, 전 안 피우셨으면 좋겠어요
Look, Mom, I wish
you wouldn't smoke.
안단다. 이게 마지막이야
약속할게
I know. This is my last one.
I promise.
그건 그렇고
By the way...
오늘 할머니 일 도와줘서 고맙다
thanks for your help
with your grandma today.
뭐 하나 물어봐도 돼요?
Can I ask you a question?
할머니는 왜 엄마를 미워하세요?
What does she have
against you, Mom?
그게..
Well...
한 25년 쯤 전에
네 아빠가 어떤 여자랑 사귀었었는데
about 25 years ago,
your father was dating...
아주 매력적이고 재주도 많아서
할머니가 좋아하셨단다
this very attractive, well-to-do woman
that your grandma liked...
그런데 아빠가 나랑 결혼한 거야
and he married me instead.
그래서 날 절대 용서 안 하신단다
And she never forgave me.
나쁜 년!
That bitch.
로렌스 윌크 쇼 테마 음악
저 솜사탕같은 옷 입은
여자는 누구였어요?
Now, who was the lady
with the cotton-candy dress?
노마 짐머라고 샴페인 아가씨란다
로렌스 윌크 쇼 도우미 아가씨 애칭
That's Norma Zimmer,
the champagne lady.
아주 매력적인데요
She is very talented.
저기 춤추는 두사람 보이지?
저건 바비하고 시시란다
And you see those two dancing?
That's Bobby and Sissy.
저 남자 쫄쫄이 바지 좋구나
I like his tight pants,
but she's a slut.
근데 저 여잔 걸레야
저 이 쇼 전에 본 적 있어요
You know, I have seen
this show before.
그런데 저 밴드 지휘자 목소리가
훨씬 남자다웠었어요
But the band leader's voice
was much more masculine.
오, 거품!
Bubbles!
번역수정: 김찬미 (husseyttl@nate)
최종수정: 김현정 (fuchs@nate)
자유배포 / 수정금지
네이트 드라마 24 자막팀
http://club.nate.com/24
자유배포 / 수정금지
네이트 드라마 24 자막팀
http://club.nate.com/24